<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OKR on Paul Blay</title><link>https://paulblay.com/tags/okr/</link><description>Recent content in OKR on Paul Blay</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 11:46:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paulblay.com/tags/okr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing the OKR ScoreCard</title><link>https://paulblay.com/blog/2021/04/05/the-okr-scorecard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://paulblay.com/blog/2021/04/05/the-okr-scorecard/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://paulblay.com/paulblay-hugo/img/OKR_Scorecard/OKRs_why-1024x227-1.png" alt="OKRs_why"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s assume we’re using OKRs now. We’ve come up with some Objectives and tried to find meaningful measures for our Key Results that we think will help us ensure we’re going in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to remind ourselves that OKRs are just a tool. Using an ORK framework doesn’t necessarily ensure that we’re getting any tangible benefits over any other approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the next two OKR examples for our imaginary TownTalk ™ product both provide an objective and measurable KRs against it, but do both really unlock the same value?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Focus on outcomes with OKRs</title><link>https://paulblay.com/blog/2020/11/17/focus-on-outcomes-with-okrs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://paulblay.com/blog/2020/11/17/focus-on-outcomes-with-okrs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in a way to tap into your team or companies creative potential, generating alignment and delivering tangible value, then OKRs should be your first port of call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to have met, and worked closely with &lt;a href="http://raganmcgill.co.uk/"&gt;Ragan McGill&lt;/a&gt; while I was at DisplayLink. Ragan had experienced both effective and underwhelming use of OKRs in his career and gave a set of training on how to ensure that they are well formed and deliver on their potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>7 Practical Steps To Increase Accountability In Agile Teams</title><link>https://paulblay.com/blog/2020/08/17/accountability-in-agile-teams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://paulblay.com/blog/2020/08/17/accountability-in-agile-teams/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Individual and team accountability is critical for any high functioning team, I believe that this is often a concern for senior management, especially when considering an agile transformation, and can be difficult to attain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the points in my career that I have seen senior management push back on the adoption of agile methodologies, the main areas of contention has been around the feeling of losing “control” over the delivery roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>