<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Autonomy on Paul Blay</title><link>https://shpinkso.github.io/paulblay-hugo/previews/main/tags/autonomy/</link><description>Recent content in Autonomy on Paul Blay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 11:46:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shpinkso.github.io/paulblay-hugo/previews/main/tags/autonomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The ugly side of no surprises management</title><link>https://shpinkso.github.io/paulblay-hugo/previews/main/blog/2019/01/05/ugly_side_no_surprises/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://shpinkso.github.io/paulblay-hugo/previews/main/blog/2019/01/05/ugly_side_no_surprises/</guid><description>I get it… I think…
“No Surprises” management is intended to ensure that people aren’t hiding bad news from their colleagues (let’s face it, usually their boss or some other superior) so that we’re not horribly surprised at the last minute that, for example, our project is 6 months late.
Boom! Instant high-functioning team! Everyone feels safe and surprises never happen…. Or at least, god help you if they still do happen, because I was very clear that I don’t like surprises!</description></item><item><title>Motivation 2.0</title><link>https://shpinkso.github.io/paulblay-hugo/previews/main/blog/2018/07/09/motivation_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://shpinkso.github.io/paulblay-hugo/previews/main/blog/2018/07/09/motivation_2/</guid><description>How are you engaging your team? Are you running a regular appraisal cycle where everyone’s individual score is totted up and ultimately dictates financial reward (pay increase, bonus, share options) or, on the other side of the scale, performance improvement plans?
How are you finding this?
Do people who get the financial rewards become more engaged and effective throughout the year? Do those on the performance improvement plans “pull their socks up” and become superstars now that they know they’re not performing to expectations?</description></item></channel></rss>