<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Delivery on Paul Blay</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/delivery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Delivery on Paul Blay</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:52:20 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/delivery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Policy for AI-enhanced software development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/07/ai_in_software_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:52:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/07/ai_in_software_development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The DORA research group at Google recently came out with an &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/ai-machine-learning/introducing-doras-inaugural-ai-capabilities-model&#34;&gt;AI capabilities model&lt;/a&gt; and capability number 1 is to have a &amp;ldquo;Clear and communicated AI stance&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Given my experience so far talking to other leaders and on the ground, here&amp;rsquo;s my proposal for what an effective AI stance could look like:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-philosophy&#34;&gt;Core Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LLMs should amplify engineering cognition, not automate it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This means&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Ownership&lt;/strong&gt;: Engineers must remain the authors and owners of production logic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Retention&lt;/strong&gt;: We preserve and grow organisational understanding rather than outsource it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognitive Augmentation&lt;/strong&gt;: Use LLMs to compress the time between &lt;em&gt;problem recognition&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;informed decision making&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;effective-augmentation-patterns&#34;&gt;Effective Augmentation Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-knowledge-synthesis--search&#34;&gt;1. Knowledge Synthesis &amp;amp; Search&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Turning documentation into an accessible, converstaional knowledge layer.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Examples&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The agility Challenge for Embedded Software</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/12/02/the-agility-challenge-for-embedded-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/12/02/the-agility-challenge-for-embedded-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever worked for a business that has it’s core focus in the embedded software space, I suspect you are more likely to have had to tolerate software development practices from 20 years ago. If you’ve read many books on Agile software development, DevOps or other modern practices, you may also have noticed that they almost all talk about software that targets a server or website, possibly a PC. But unless you’re reading a very different library to me, you’ll not have seen much talk about embedded software. Why is this?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Practical Steps To Increase Accountability In Agile Teams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/08/17/accountability-in-agile-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/08/17/accountability-in-agile-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Individual and team accountability is critical for any high functioning team, I believe that this is often a concern for senior management, especially when considering an agile transformation, and can be difficult to attain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the points in my career that I have seen senior management push back on the adoption of agile methodologies, the main areas of contention has been around the feeling of losing “control” over the delivery roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the bottleneck is everything</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018/09/12/why_bottleneck_everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018/09/12/why_bottleneck_everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is probably the least intuitive idea that I’ve come across in my working career, but when explained and demonstrated, possibly one of the most important.&#xA;Here it is: it is inefficient to have everyone working at 100% effort, 100% of the time.&#xA;This seems wrong – we’re paying for these people, they should be putting all their time and effort towards our product features! Get back to working on them! However, due to a concept called the “theory of constraints” (see “The Goal” by E.M. Goldratt) this is actually a terribly inefficient way of getting value through your business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motivation 2.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018/07/09/motivation_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018/07/09/motivation_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How are you engaging your team? Are you running a regular appraisal cycle where everyone’s individual score is totted up and ultimately dictates financial reward (pay increase, bonus, share options) or, on the other side of the scale, performance improvement plans?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How are you finding this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do people who get the financial rewards become more engaged and effective throughout the year? Do those on the performance improvement plans “pull their socks up” and become superstars now that they know they’re not performing to expectations?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what is agility?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017/02/03/what_is_agility/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 11:46:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017/02/03/what_is_agility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strictly speaking, ‘agile’ is an adjective, a descriptive word… like “nimble” &amp;amp; so the more obvious title “What is agile?” probably would have made a small, hardcore, fraction of people up-chuck a little in their mouths. (I am not so offended on this one, but tell me something is “addicting” and I will develop an unruly lower eyelid twitch). I think the reason behind this is due to how commercialised and corporate the term has become over the years – ironically, as the original manifesto moved thinking in a completely different direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
